<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Scoiatael&#39;s braindump</title>
    <link>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Scoiatael&#39;s braindump</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 12:58:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bd.scoiatael.dev/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea: matrix log analyzer</title>
      <link>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/projects/matrix-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 12:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/projects/matrix-logs/</guid>
      <description>Recently I came up an interesting project: cxxmatrix. It creates matrix-like animations in your terminal. This prompted a train of thought: it&#39;s neat, but in the movie it had a purpose. It was used like a tail -f /var/log/messages: a real-time glimpse into what&#39;s currently happening inside the Matrix.
Can we somehow make it a useful reality? My latest PITA has been exactly that: looking into trails of logs in order to find patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parrhasius</title>
      <link>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/projects/parrhasius/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 17:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/projects/parrhasius/</guid>
      <description>One day I found myself scrolling through internet best source of wallpapers and found myself wishing for something to mass-download a whole thread. Without a proper google search even, decided to write something on my own. Presto! A new project.
Part 1: Good beginnings The basic part is easy enough: use Nokogiri in Ruby to parse site HTML, extract image URLs:
html = Nokogiri(open(link).read) html.search(&amp;#39;a&amp;#39;) .select { |l| l.children.size == 1 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; l.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/projects/blog-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 19:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/projects/blog-start/</guid>
      <description>What? Decided to start a blog. Nothing fancy, more like a braindump. All the ideas for projects which are currently in various TODO programs (Google Keep, Todoiost, Wunderlist) and org files, some descriptions for already writen projects with links. Maybe some ramblings around random thoughts.
Why? Of all the weird places I could get motivation from, the thought occured when reading RFC. A pretty special one, for that: RFC 8700 - Fifty Years of RFCs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>