<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My treasure cove. on Scoiatael&#39;s braindump</title>
    <link>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My treasure cove. on Scoiatael&#39;s braindump</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 12:58:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bd.scoiatael.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea: matrix log analyzer</title>
      <link>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/projects/matrix-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 12:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/projects/matrix-logs/</guid>
      <description>Recently I came upon an interesting project: cxxmatrix. It creates matrix-like animations in your terminal. This prompted a train of thought: it&#39;s neat, but in the movie it had a purpose. It was used like a tail -f /var/log/messages: a real-time glimpse into what&#39;s currently happening inside the Matrix.
Can we somehow make it a useful reality? My latest PITA has been exactly that: looking into trails of logs in order to find patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Python tooling</title>
      <link>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/rants/state-of-python-tooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 21:39:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/rants/state-of-python-tooling/</guid>
      <description>Recently I joined a team working mostly in Python. As usual, one of the first steps is getting development environment for the projects up and running. The first part was quick and easy: download a couple of config files &amp;amp; secrets, docker-compose up and we are up and running.
Then came the hard part: getting local Python environment running for tests and code-completion.
Preface I&#39;m a big fan of direnv - having single .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software architecture</title>
      <link>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/rants/software-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 14:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/rants/software-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Recently I began to wonder why is building software that interesting? I quite enjoy computer and tabletop games, and somehow simply building software seems to be at least as challenging and in turn rewarding.
The obvious answer: joy of creation Though I haven&#39;t done any research in that area, I&#39;m quite sure that in general people like creating - and by that expressing themselves, and losing themselves in the process. It seems a bit far-fetched to compare painting to writing code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parrhasius</title>
      <link>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/projects/parrhasius/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 17:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/projects/parrhasius/</guid>
      <description>One day I found myself scrolling through internet best source of wallpapers and found myself wishing for something to mass-download a whole thread. Without a proper google search even, decided to write something on my own. Presto! A new project.
Part 1: Good beginnings The basic part is easy enough: use Nokogiri in Ruby to parse site HTML, extract image URLs:
html = Nokogiri(open(link).read) html.search(&amp;#39;a&amp;#39;) .select { |l| l.children.size == 1 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; l.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/projects/blog-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 19:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/projects/blog-start/</guid>
      <description>What? Decided to start a blog. Nothing fancy, more like a braindump. All the ideas for projects which are currently in various TODO programs (Google Keep, Todoiost, Wunderlist) and org files, some descriptions for already writen projects with links. Maybe some ramblings around random thoughts.
Why? Of all the weird places I could get motivation from, the thought occured when reading RFC. A pretty special one, for that: RFC 8700 - Fifty Years of RFCs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credits</title>
      <link>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/credits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/credits/</guid>
      <description>Splash screen Photo by rohro clark on Unsplash.
Hugo theme Credit to Bud Parr.
Org-&amp;gt;hugo export Credit to Kaushal Modi.
Favicon Generated using favicon.io.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things Puppet won&#39;t tell you about Deferred</title>
      <link>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/rants/puppet-deferred/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bd.scoiatael.dev/rants/puppet-deferred/</guid>
      <description>You might&#39;ve heard about one of Puppet 6&#39;s freshfeatures: Deferred. It basically allows you to run code on agent during execution, instead of only on master during compilation.
It&#39;s awesome for many reasons; you can:
 retrieve secrets on agents, implement lazy execution and macros,  But it has one big problem. Let me show what&#39;s wrong.
Usage Try writing an example code with Deferred:
# manifest.pp$args = { now_on_master =&amp;gt; new(TimeStamp), shadow_contents =&amp;gt; Deferred(&amp;#39;file&amp;#39;, [&amp;#39;/etc/puppet_time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>